ALYSSA WILLIAMS

206-683-3108

alyssajanelwilliams@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/ajwilliams12/en https://github.com/alyssaw90

Profile

Upon graduating in 2012, I started my career in physical therapy. Working in physical therapy clinics I gained experience working with patients and health insurance. During this time I started thinking about how technology could change and improve the world. I started to teach myself how to code and I have completed the General Assembly Web Development Immersive Course.

Skills

• Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, HTML, CSS, LESS/SASS

• Frameworks: Node.js, Express JS, Rails, AngularJS, Sailsjs, React.js

• Database Tools: SQL, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, ActiveRecord

• Authorization: Bcrypt

• Testing Frameworks: RSpec

• Other: WordPress, Git/GitHub, Heroku, jQuery, AJAX, JSON, Bootstrap, Microsoft Office Suite

Experience

HEALTHY BEEPS, FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER (CONTRACT) 2015-PRESENT

Healthy Beeps is a startup that is developing a site for patients to find reviews and purchase consumer medical devices. I am responsible for building out the front end UI and some of the backend components. I am working with Node.js, React.js, LESS, and more. I work directly with the CTO and CEO in order to complete tasks in a timely manner.

GENERAL ASSEMBLY, TEACHER ASSISTANT 2015-PRESENT

I help out the instructors and students in the web development immersive course in the evenings. I help students with homework, labs, and explaining concepts further that they have learned that day.

AFFIRMA CONSULTING, SITE BUILDER/FRONT END DEVELOPER 2015

I work directly with project managers and clients to help develop the client facing side of web applications and Sharepoint sites. I also help in troubleshooting different problems. I mainly use HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, and jQuery. I have worked with a variety of clients including Microsoft and Cross Country Healthcare.

GENERAL ASSEMBLY, WEB DEVELOPMENT IMMERSIVE COURSE 2014-2015

It is a 12 week intense and immersive course that teaches different languages and frameworks. During this course we are learning JavaScript, Express JS, Node.js, Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, and more. Also we 3 individual and group projects are completed during the course.

DIRECTOR OF REHAB ASSISTANT, INFINITY REHAB 2014

The facility was a large 140 bed facility where I worked directly with therapy, nursing, and office staff. My duties included completing the daily therapy schedule, keep compliance/HIPAA regulations up to date, keep DOR and therapy team organized, attend meetings, address patient, family and therapists concerns.

EXERCISE SPECIALIST, MARRAN PHYSICAL THERAPY 2013-2014

I worked directly with patients and the therapy team. My duties included starting patients, set up patient rooms, help patients with rehabilitation program, set patient up on different modalities, keep clinic organized/clean, help at front desk, and order supplies.

PHYSICAL THERAPY AIDE, PROLIANCE SPORTS THERAPY 2012-2013

I worked directly with patients and the therapy team. My duties included starting patients, set up patient rooms, help patients with rehabilitation program, set patient up on different modalities, keep clinic organized/clean, and, help at front desk.

Education

UNIVERSITY OF PORTLAND, PORTLAND, OREGON — LIFE SCIENCE B.S., 2012